The Swimmers is a drama, history film directed by Sally El Hosaini.
From war-torn Syria to the 2016 Rio Olympics, two young sisters embark on a risky
voyage, putting their hearts and their swimming skills to heroic use.
Sarah Mardini, played by Manal Issa.
Yusra Mardini, played by Nathalie Issa.
Sven, played by Matthias Schweighöfer.
Ezzat Mardini, played by Ali Suliman.
Emad, played by James Floyd.
Nizar, played by Ahmed Malek.
The Swimmers is a 2022 biographical sports drama film directed by Sally
El Hosaini, who co-wrote the screenplay with Jack Thorne.
The film stars real-life sisters Nathalie Issa and Manal Issa, Ahmed Malek, Matthias
Schweighöfer, Ali Suliman, Kinda Alloush, James Krishna Floyd, and Elmi Rashid Elmi.
The film follows two young sisters who embark on a risky voyage from war-torn Syria to Rio
de Janeiro, Brazil, as one of them competes in the 2016 Summer Olympics.
The Swimmers premiered at the 2022 Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2022, and was
released in select cinemas on November 11 before its streaming release on November 23, by Netflix.
The film was nominated at the 2023 BAFTA film awards for Outstanding British Film, received positive reviews from
critics and was a global hit on Netflix, achieving no.1 in 15 countries and top 10 in 85 countries.
The film explores themes of refugee, olympian sports team,
biography, based on true story, family relationships.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.